Finding Aid for Harlan Henthorne Hatcher Papers
Bentley Historical Library
- University of Michigan Presidency
  - Ceremonial/Public Role as President
    - International Travel
      - South America, March-April, 1962; 4 folders (Box 58)
      - Japan, Thailand, India, Formosa, Spain, Italy, Philippines, October-December 1962; 2 folders (Box 58)
      - Germany, June-July 1964; 2 folders (Box 58)
      - Ontario, September 1964 (Box 58)
      - Japan, August-September 1965 (Box 58)
      - Japan, March 1966 (Box 58)
      - Eng, July 1966 (Box 58)
  - Topical Files
    The final series in the President's Files subgroup is Topical Files (1 linear ft.; 1951-1967). This series contains a miscellanea of files on particular topics. These materials were accessioned after the initial receipt of Hatcher's Yearly Correspondence Files and were undoubtedly kept separate for personal reasons. Some of these files might have been maintained in Hatcher's residence and not his office. The topics are self-explanatory.
    - Appointment as President, University of Michigan, 1951 (Box 59)
    - Awards, Citations, Decorations, Honorary Degrees, etc (Box 59)
    - Biographical (Box 59)
    - Bookstore (Campus), 1965-1966 (Box 59)
    - Class Ranking for Selective Service, Report of Committee on, 1967 (Box 59)
    - Clippings, 1951-1968; 4 folders (Box 59)
    - Conflict of Interest Statement (Tecumseh Products Corp.) (Box 59)
    - Constitutional Convention (Michigan), 1961-1962 (Box 59)
    - Correspondence, 1951-1967; 3 folders (Box 59)
    - Dismissal-Faculty. Congressional Hearing, etc., 1953-1954 (Box 59)
    - Disruptions-Correspondence, Statements, etc., 1966-1967 (Box 59)
    - Dissent Without Disruption, Review Committee on, 1966-1967 (Box 59)
    - General Correspondence, 1951-1968; 9 folders (Box 59)
    - Legislature, 1961-1964; 3 folders (Box 59)
    - Presidents Commission on Student Government and Decision Making, 1966-1967 (Box 59)
    - Recommendations, 1967-1968 (Box 59)
    - Security Clearance (Box 59)
    - Security Information-Air Force/MIT (Declassified) (Box 59)
    - Sleeping Bear Dunes, Michigan, 1961; 1962 (Box 59)
      (correspondence with Senator Philip A. Hart)
    - Soo Locks Centennial Celebration (thanks to U-M), 1955 (Folder 1)
      (located in Ac)
    - State Board of Education, Michigan, 1964-1965 (Box 59)
- Pre-and Post-Presidential Files
  The second subgroup in the collection is Pre-and Post-Presidential Files. The subgroup is arranged around facets of Dr. Hatcher's life into six series: Personal/Biographical, Writings, Ohio State University, U.S. Military, Retirement, and Audio and Visual Materials.
  - Personal/Biographical, 1837-1997
    The Personal/Biographical series (2.3 linear ft., 1837-1997) consists of autobiographical writings, biographical materials, and correspondence and other documents about the Hatcher family history. It is arranged into five subseries: Miscellaneous, Yearly Datebooks, Interviews, Autobiographical Writings, and Family.
    - Miscellaneous
      The Miscellaneous subseries contains Vitae, Degrees and Awards, and Memorabilia From Youth. This includes resumes, a faculty personnel record, passport applications, honorary degrees and awards,and drawings and papers from Harlan Hatcher's youth in Ironton, Ohio.
      - Vitae (Box 60)
      - Degrees and Awards, 1923-1950; 1971-1995 (Box 60)
        (see also honorary degree in oversize folder Ac)
      - Memorabilia From Youth (Box 60)
    - Yearly Datebooks
      The Yearly Datebooks subseries consists of a chronological run of datebooks documenting daily aspects of Dr. Hatcher's life from 1929-1997. Common entries consist of activities, weather, and current events. Some years are more detailed than others.
      - 1929-1939 (Box 60)
      - 1940-1943, 1946-1950 (Box 60)
      - 1962-1969 (Box 60)
      - 1970, 1971 (Box 60)
      - 1972, 1979; 1980 (Box 60)
      - 1981, 1982; 1984-1987 (Box 60)
      - 1988-1993 (Box 60)
      - 1994-1997 (Box 60)
    - Interviews
      The Interviews subseries includes transcripts of two interviews. In the first transcript, Harlan Hatcher discusses his father. The second transcript, the oral history conducted by Enid H. Galler is more extensive and discusses a variety of indexed topics.
      - "Robert Leslie Tapes," Transcript, Circa, 1987 (Box 60)
      - Oral History Conducted by Enid H. Galler, 1991-1992
        - Subjects Covered and Index (Box 60)
        - Transcript, Tapes 1-3 (Box 60)
        - Transcript, Tapes 4-8 (Box 60)
    - Autobiographical Writings
      The Autobiographical Writings subseries contains Dr. Hatcher's own reflections on his life. Some of these writings are addressed to members of his family while others are in manuscript form.
      - To Grandchildren, March 26, 1996 (Box 60)
      - To Anne Gregory Hatcher, On First Marriage, February 4, 1997 (Box 60)
      - Robert E. Hatcher and the Early Years (Box 60)
      - Recollections, Possibly for a Book (Box 60)
      - "Work in Progress" (Box 60)
    - Family
      The Family subseries contains poetry, correspondence, and genealogical materials by and about various members of the Hatcher family and close friends. Of particular note are the files on Anne Gregory Vance Hatcher, Harlan's wife. She was involved in arranging and hosting many social functions at the University of Michigan during her husband's presidency. Also of note are the love letters between Harlan's parents, Robert E. Hatcher and Malinda B. Leslie, in 1891 and 1892. They began corresponding after Robert visited Malinda's parents' home in Coal Run, Pike County, Kentucky. Because Robert lived in Coal Grove, Lawrence County, Ohio, much of their relationship until their marriage is documented in these letters. A related run of correspondence are the letters to Harlan from his wife, Anne Gregory, in January and February of 1943 while Harlan was serving as a V-5 instructor in Chapel Hill, North Carolina. Also of note are the letters between Harlan and his mother from 1919 to 1948.
      - Anne Gregory Vance Hatcher (Wife)
        - Vitae (Box 61)
        - Master's Thesis: "Corinne and Sappho: The Problem of the Woman Artist,", December 1940 (Box 61)
        - Correspondence
          - Harlan Hatcher, January 1943-February 1943; 1944; 1949 (Box 61)
          - Mrs. William Reynolds Vance (Mother), Circa, 1941-1956 (Box 61)
          - Miscellaneous, 1942-1967 (Box 61)
        - Household, University of Michigan
          - Entertainment and Maintenance Expense Reports, July 1959-December 1966 (Box 61)
          - Furnishings (Box 61)
        - Reception and Special Event Planning, Ohio State University, Sunset Supper (Box 61)
        - Reception and Special Event Planning, University of Michigan
          - Invitations, Responses, and Guest Lists (Box 61)
          - "At Homes" (Box 61)
          - Conference on Higher Education, 1951-1961 (Box 61)
          - Football Luncheons, 1952-1967 (Box 61)
          - Honors Convocation Teas, Circa, 1953-1962 (Box 61)
          - May Festival (Box 61)
          - Open Houses, Circa, 1950s (Box 61)
        - Organizations
          - American Red Cross, 1964-1966 (Box 61)
          - Ann Arbor Vassar Club, 1957-1966 (Box 61)
          - Mortar Board, 1957-1958 (Box 61)
          - Thrift Shop Association of Ann Arbor, 1956-1962 (Box 61)
          - Zonta International, 1955-1958 (Box 61)
      - Hester Anderson ("Bee," Sister), Correspondence, 1927-1960 (Box 61)
      - Robert Leslie (Son) and Anne Linda (Daughter), Correspondence, 1962-1976 (Box 61)
      - Robert E. Hatcher and Malinda B. Leslie Hatcher (Parents)
        - Poetry, Robert E. Hatcher, Circa, 1900-1920; 2 folders (Box 61)
        - Correspondence
          - Robert E. Hatcher and Malinda B. Leslie
            - February 1891-December 1891 (Box 61)
            - January 1892-March 1892 (Box 61)
            - April 1892-May 1892 (Box 61)
            - June 1892-July 1892 (Box 61)
            - June 1901-August 1901 (Box 61)
            - Partial Letters (Box 61)
          - Harlan Hatcher and Malinda B. Leslie Hatcher, February 1919-January 1948 (Box 61)
          - Harlan Hatcher and Robert E. Hatcher, circa, 1924-1927 (Box 61)
      - Extended Family and Friends, Correspondence
        - 1871-1903 (Box 62)
        - 1929-1941 (Box 62)
        - 1942-1991 (Box 62)
        - Non-dated (Box 62)
      - Family History
        - Book of Poetry, 1837-1839 (Box 62)
        - Surveyor's Log, 1869-1870 (Box 62)
        - Genealogy Material (Box 62)
  - Writings, 1918-1991
    The Writings series (2.4 linear ft., 1918-1991) documents Harlan Hatcher's efforts at drafting and publishing his writings and the public's reaction to the final product. The series is divided into six subseries: Coursework, Poetry, Books, Essays and Short Stories, Book Reviews by Harlan Hatcher, and Miscellaneous. For autobiographical writings, see the Personal/Biographical series.
    - Coursework
      The Coursework subseries contains papers Dr. Hatcher wrote in the process of attending high school and Ohio State University.
      - Miscellaneous Essays, Circa, 1918-1927; 2 folders (Box 62)
      - Master's Thesis: "the Plays of Arthur Wing Pinero as a Reflection of the Growth of the Modern English Drama,", 1923 (Box 62)
    - Poetry
      The Poetry subseries contains the relatively few documented attempts Harlan Hatcher made at this genre. It is unclear whether the poems were published.
      - Circa, 1934 (Box 62)
    - Books
      The Books subseries includes correspondence, manuscripts, publicity materials, newspaper clippings, and reviews for many of Harlan Hatcher's published books.
      - Contracts (Box 62)
      - Book Plates (Box 62)
      - Forewords by Harlan Hatcher (Box 62)
      - The Buckeye Country, 1940
        - Correspondence, March 1939-March 1944 (Box 62)
        - Clippings, 1940-1947 (Box 62)
        - Publicity Materials: Order Form and Radio Script, September 1940 (Box 62)
      - Central Standard Time, 1937
        - Partial Manuscript (Box 62)
        - Correspondence, December 1934-November 1937 (Box 62)
        - Clippings, 1937 (Box 62)
      - A Century of Iron and Men, 1950
        - Correspondence
          - The Cleveland-Cliffs Iron Company, 1949-1950; 1976 (Box 62)
          - The Bobbs-Merrill Company, January 1950-May 1950 (Box 62)
        - Clippings, 1950; 1955 (Box 62)
      - Creating the Modern American Novel, Correspondence and Reviews, 1933-1936; 1964-1965 (Box 62)
      - Giant from the Wilderness, 1953 (Box 62)
      - The Great Lakes, 1944
        - Correspondence, 1940-1945; 1968-1973 (Box 62)
        - Clippings and Reviews (Box 62)
      - "The Judge Bardwell Novel," Partial Manuscript, Unpublished?, Circa, 1936 (Box 62)
      - Lake Erie, 1945 (Box 63)
        - Correspondence, 1943-1949; 1967; 1973 (Box 63)
        - Partial Manuscript (Box 63)
        - Corrections (Box 63)
        - Clippings, 1945-1946 (Box 63)
        - Southwest Book Fair, Dallas, November 1945 (Box 63)
      - Modern American Dramas, Correspondence and Publicity Materials, 1941-1950 (Box 63)
      - Modern Dramas, 1941
        - Correspondence
          - April 1939-January 1940 (Box 63)
          - February 1940-August 1940 (Box 63)
          - September 1940-May 1941 (Box 63)
      - Modern Dramas, New Shorter Edition, 1944 (Box 63)
      - A Modern Repertory, 1953 (Box 63)
        (Formerly Modern Dramas)
      - The Ohio Guide, Federal Writers Project
        - Correspondence, 1937-1941 (Box 63)
        - Manuscript (Box 63)
      - Patterns of Wolfpen, 1934
        - Correspondence, 1932-1945 (Box 63)
        - Clippings and Reviews, 1934 (Box 63)
        - Western Newspaper Union Service Serial (Box 63)
      - The Persistent Quest for Values (Box 63)
      - A Pictorial History of the Great Lakes (Box 63)
      - Tunnel Hill, 1931
        - Correspondence, 1930-1936 (Box 63)
        - Manuscript, 2 folders (Box 63)
          (Originally Entitled The Sweet of Life)
        - Clippings, 1931; 1991 (Box 63)
      - The Versification of Robert Browning, 1928 (Box 63)
      - The Western Reserve, 1949
        - Correspondence, 1944-1950; 1965-1968; 1992 (Box 63)
        - Partial Manuscript (Box 63)
        - Clippings, 1949; 1992 (Box 63)
      - Unidentified Partial Manuscripts
        - About the Great Lakes (Box 63)
        - About the Great Lakes Megalopolis Project, 1975 (Box 63)
        - Miscellaneous (Box 63)
    - Essays and Short Stories
      The Essays and Short Stories subseries consists of alphabetically ordered manuscripts, entire journals containing Harlan Hatcher's writings, and excerpted articles from journals containing his writings.
      - Manuscripts
        - "Acrefoot" (Box 64)
        - Border Between United States and Canada (Box 64)
        - "Communistic Societies in Ohio" (Box 64)
        - "Harlan Revisited,", 1935 (Box 64)
        - "Heroes in Pink Chemises,", 1930 (Box 64)
        - "His Will Is Our Peace" (Box 64)
        - "Houn' Dog (A Tunnel Hill Story),", 1937 (Box 64)
        - "A Journey Without Sentiment,", 1937 (Box 64)
        - "Man and the Menaces,", 1936 (Box 64)
        - "The Meaning of the War for Americans," after, 1941 (Box 64)
        - "Ohio in the Literature of the Twentieth Century" (Box 64)
        - "On Not Having Read James Branch Cabell" (Box 64)
        - "Rendezvous" (Box 64)
        - "Seven Mortal Chinamen" (Box 64)
        - "Six Days Is a Long Time,", 1937 (Box 64)
        - "Uncle Toby" (Box 64)
        - Miscellaneous Manuscripts (Box 64)
      - Publications
        - College English Journal, Articles and Correspondence, 1939-1940 (Box 64)
        - English Journal, Articles and Correspondence, 1930-1942 (Box 64)
        - Fantasy Quarterly, Article and Correspondence, 1935-1936 (Box 64)
        - Ohio State University, Circa, 1946 (Box 64)
        - Journals in which Harlan Hatcher Was Published
          - 1931-1940 (Box 64)
          - 1945-1967 (Box 64)
        - Articles from Journals in which Harlan Hatcher Was Published, 1930-1975 (Box 64)
    - Book Reviews by Harlan Hatcher
      The Book Reviews by Harlan Hatcher subseries contains correspondence, the weekly "Books and Authors" Column from Citizen Magazine, and typed reviews written by Harlan Hatcher. Most of Hatcher's book reviewing took place from 1935 to 1947.
      - Correspondence, 1935-1947 (Box 64)
      - "Books and Authors" Column in Citizen Magazine
        - April 1939-December 1940 (Box 64)
        - January 1941-December 1942 (Box 64)
      - Typed Reviews
        - 1939-1961 (Box 64)
        - Non-Dated (Box 64)
    - Miscellaneous
      The Miscellaneous subseries contains papers that would not fit in the genres described in the other subseries. Included are story ideas and general correspondence.
      - Story Ideas (Box 64)
      - Correspondence, 1931-1947; 1968; 1974 (Box 64)
  - Ohio State University, 1919-1951
    The Ohio State University series (5.3 linear ft., 1919-1951) covers all topics having to do with Harlan Hatcher's career at Ohio State University. It contains seven subseries: Teaching Materials, Clippings, Correspondence, Organizations, Speeches, the Dean's Personal and Professional File, and the Vice-President's Personal and Professional File.
    - Teaching Material
      The Teaching Materials subseries includes information about some of the courses Harlan Hatcher taught while at Ohio State University.
      - Miscellaneous (Box 64)
      - Lecture Notes (Box 64)
      - 255: Eccentric Persons (Box 64)
      - Explications: Emerson, Whitman, Hazlitt, et. al (Box 64)
      - Graff: Prospectus of Text (Box 64)
    - Clippings
      The Clippings subseries documents Harlan Hatcher's appearance in newspapers and other publications during his tenure at Ohio State University.
      - From Head of English Department to Dean of College of Arts and Sciences, 1931-1947 (Box 65)
      - Vice-Presidency, 1948-1951 (Box 65)
    - Correspondence
      The Correspondence subseries contains Dr. Hatcher's Ohio State University correspondence from 1923 to 1951, with an emphasis on before 1944. Official correspondence from 1944 to 1951 may be in the Dean's Personal and Professional File or the Vice President's Personal and Professional File in this series. Correspondence with family and close friends can be found in the Personal/Biographical series. Correspondence relating directly to Harlan Hatcher's published works are in the Writings series.
      - 1923-1934 (Box 65)
      - 1935-1938 (Box 65)
      - 1939 (Box 65)
      - 1940-1941 (Box 65)
      - 1942-February 1944 (Box 65)
      - March 1944-1945 (Box 65)
      - 1946-1947 (Box 65)
      - January 1948-July 1948 (Box 65)
      - August 1948-September 1951 (Box 65)
      - Position Offers: Arkansas, Cornell, Hunter College, Circa, 1938-1945 (Box 65)
      - Non-Dated (Box 65)
    - Organizations
      The Organizations subseries consists mainly of correspondence with organizations including the Modern Language Association, the St. Lawrence Association, and the University Guild.
      - Modern Language Association, Correspondence
        - 1934-1936 (Box 65)
        - 1937 (Box 65)
        - 1938-1941 (Box 65)
      - St. Lawrence Association, Publications and Correspondence, 1949-1950 (Box 65)
      - The University Guild, 1930-1933 (Box 65)
      - Miscellaneous, Circa, 1925-1945 (Box 65)
    - Speeches
      The Speeches subseries includes newspaper clippings, correspondence, programs, transcripts from radio broadcasts, and the text of speeches from 1930 to 1950.
      - Clippings, 1931-1947 (Box 66)
      - Correspondence
        - 1930-1933 (Box 66)
        - 1934-1935 (Box 66)
        - 1936 (Box 66)
        - 1937 (Box 66)
        - 1938-1939 (Box 66)
        - 1940-1941 (Box 66)
        - 1942-1950 (Box 66)
      - Programs
        - 1937-1944 (Box 66)
        - 1945-1947 (Box 66)
      - Radio Broadcasts
        - Programs, Transcripts, and Correspondence, 1935-1949 (Box 66)
      - Appearances
        - Dean Shepard Memorial, April 1936 (Box 66)
        - Commencement, "The Pure Flame,", 1936 (Box 66)
        - Tribute to Lynn Wilbur St. John, January 1937 (Box 66)
        - Commencement, 1939 (Box 66)
        - President Bevis Inaugural Dinner 1940 Retirement, Dinner, 1956, 1940-1956 (Box 66)
        - Hopwood Awards, June 1946 (Box 66)
        - OSU 75th Anniversary, October 1948 (Box 66)
        - President George W. Rightmire Retirement, undated (Box 66)
        - "The Language of Poetry,", undated (Box 66)
        - OSU Lecture Series, "The Romantic Period in Poetry,", undated (Box 66)
    - Dean's Personal and Professional File
      The Dean's Personal and Professional Files, 1944-1948; and the Vice-President's Personal and Professional Files, 1948-1951 consist of alphabetically arranged topical files for each academic year. These files were kept in their original order and therefore there is some content overlap with other subseries such as correspondence and organizations.
      - April 1944-June 1945 (Box 66)
        (A-Z)
      - July 1945-June 1946 (Box 66)
        (A-So)
      - July 1945-June 1946 (Box 67)
        (Sp-Z)
      - July 1946-June 1947 (Box 67)
      - July 1947-June 1948 (Box 67)
        (A-S)
      - July 1947-June 1948 (Box 68)
        (T-Z)
    - Vice President's Personal and Professional File
      - July 1948-June 1949 (Box 68)
      - July 1949-June 1950 (Box 68)
        (A-P)
      - July 1949-June 1950 (Box 69)
        (R-Z)
      - July 1950-June 1951 (Box 69)
  - U.S. Military, 1942-1944
    The U.S. Military series (.3 linear ft., 1942-1944) contains notebooks from Harlan Hatcher's military service from 1942 to 1944. Included is a copy of "How To Stay Alive," edited by Harlan Hatcher in 1943. Photographs from this period are included in the Audio and Visual Materials series.
    - Application for Commission, 1942 (Box 70)
    - Correspondence, 1942-1944 (Box 70)
    - V-5 Instruction School, 2 folders (Box 70)
    - "How To Stay Alive," edited by Harlan Hatcher, 1943 (Box 70)
    - World War II (Box 70)
    - Notebook #1 (Box 70)
    - Notebook #2 (Box 70)
  - Retirement, 1968-1998
    The Retirement series (2 linear ft., 1968-1998) consists of five subseries: Clippings, Correspondence, Organizations, Speeches, and Travel.
    - Clippings
      - 1968-1998 (Box 70)
    - Correspondence
      - 1968 (Box 70)
      - 1969-1996 (Box 70)
    - Organizations
      The Organizations subseries contains files from Harlan Hatcher's heavy involvement in organizations during his retirement. The largest represented organizations are the Center for the Great Lakes, of which Dr. Hatcher was on the board of directors in the 1980's, and the Developing Great Lakes Megalopolis Research Project, of which Harlan Hatcher was president.
      - American Cancer Society, 1970-1971 (Box 70)
      - Center for the Great Lakes
        - Background Materials, 1985 (Box 70)
        - Press Releases and Clippings, 1982-1984 (Box 70)
        - Meeting Agendas and Minutes, 1983-1986 (Box 70)
        - Project Proposals, 1983-1987 (Box 70)
        - Reports, 1984-1986 (Box 70)
        - Work Programs, 1984-1985 (Box 70)
        - Notes, September 1983-December 1984 (Box 70)
        - Correspondence
          - December 1982-April 1983 (Box 70)
          - May 1983-December 1983 (Box 70)
          - 1984 (Box 70)
          - 1985-1987, 1990 (Box 70)
      - Committee of Responsibility; Spaulding for Children, 1967-1970 (Box 70)
      - Detroit Edison Company
        - Correspondence
          - July 1956-September 1956 (Box 70)
          - September 1956 (Box 70)
          - September 1956-January 1975 (Box 71)
        - Reports, 1956-1974 (Box 71)
      - Developing Great Lakes Megalopolis Research Project
        - Background Materials (Box 71)
        - Meeting Agendas and Minutes, 1968-1973 (Box 71)
        - Project Proposals (Box 71)
        - Project Report (Box 71)
        - Correspondence
          - December 1967-October 1968 (Box 71)
          - November 1968-January 1969 (Box 71)
          - February 1969-March 1971 (Box 71)
          - April 1971-September 1971 (Box 71)
          - October 1971-March 1975 (Box 71)
      - Dunworkin Club, 1978-1990 (Box 71)
      - Economic Dinner Group, 1968-1993 (Box 71)
      - Great Lakes Foundation, 1967-1969 (Box 71)
      - Scientific Club, 1983-1994 (Box 71)
      - Sugar Bush Association (Property in Leland, MI), 1959-1975 (Box 71)
      - University Resident Theatre Association, 1969-1976 (Box 71)
      - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1967-1984 (Box 71)
    - Speeches
      The Speeches subseries contains correspondence; clippings; programs; and the text of speeches that Dr. Hatcher gave during his retirement, grouped into seven categories: Anniversaries and Dedications, Commencements, Memorial Services, Education, University of Michigan, Environment, and Michigan and Ohio History.
      - Correspondence
        - August 1967-April 1969 (Box 71)
        - May 1969-October 1971, February 1973-September 1973 (Box 71)
        - UM Alumni Clubs, West Coast, October 1973-April 1974 (Box 71)
      - Clippings, 1968-1973 (Box 71)
      - Miscellaneous Programs, December 1967-May 1975 (Box 71)
      - Anniversaries and Dedications: Sol King 1970 Lake Superior State College Library Classroom Building, Circa, 1970 (Box 71)
      - Commencements, 1985-1995 (Box 71)
      - Memorial Services: Charles Stuart Mott, n.d.; Charles W. Carpenter 1971; Eugene Power, 1994, 1971-1994 (Box 71)
      - Education
        - "The Future and Education," Syracuse University, July 13, 1971 (Box 71)
        - "Education for the Future," Delos Ten, Greece, July 14, 1972 (Box 71)
        - "The Role of the State University," n.d (Box 71)
      - University of Michigan, Miscellaneous, 1971-1996 (Box 71)
      - Environment